Guide to the New Day Films Archive, 1969-2018 RL.10180
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Digital Films Collection, 1971-2018; 12 Terabytes 214 digital files
  - Syjuco, Marty
    - Give Up Tommorow, 2009; 96 minutes (Digital-materials RL10180-SET-0087_u, Video-file SyjucoMarty_GiveUpTommorow.mp4)
      Simultaneously a murder-mystery and an exposè of endemic corruption today, Give Up Tomorrow looks intimately at the case of Paco Larrañaga, a student accused of killing two sisters on the provincial island of Cebu. In a way that is both specific to the country and disquietingly universal, the film exposes a Kafkaesque extravaganza populated by flamboyantly crooked public officials, cops on the take, and a frenzied legal and media circus. Give Up Tomorrow is also an intimate family drama focused on the near mythic struggle of two angry, sorrowful mothers who have dedicated more than a decade to executing or saving one young man. Their irreconcilable versions of justice play out in a controversial case, dubbed "The Trial of the Century", that ends a country's use of capital punishment, yet fails to free an innocent man. Give Up Tomorrow is an Emmy® Award nominated documentary for Outstanding Investigative Journalism and a finalist for the Puma Impact Award. Produced by Michael Collins.
    - Almost Sunrise, 2014; 93 minutes (Digital-materials RL10180-SET-0087_u, Video-file SyjucoMarty_AlmostSunrise.mp4)
      A rare, hopeful look at the life of a veteran, beyond his demons – from the Emmy® Award nominated creators of Give Up Tomorrow. Almost Sunrise follows two Iraq veterans, Tom Voss and Anthony Anderson, who struggle with depression after returning home from service. Fearful of succumbing to the epidemic of veteran suicide (20 each day), they seek a lifeline and embark on a physical and spiritual journey across America as a way to confront their inner pain. The film captures an intimate portrait of two friends, suffering from the invisible wounds of war, as they discover unlikely treatments: the healing effect of community, and the restorative power of silence and meditation. Produced by Michael Collins.
  - Symons, Johnny
    - Beauty Before Age, 1998; 22 minutes (Digital-materials RL10180-SET-0088_u, Video-file SymonsJohnny_BeautyBeforeAge.mp4)
      The film critically examines the pressure to look young and attractive, lack of positive older role models and ways in which AIDS intensifies the fear and process of aging. Beauty Before Age offers a male perspective on a historically female issue and illuminates the larger societal obsession with physical appearance.
    - Daddy and Papa, 2002; 57 minutes (Digital-materials RL10180-SET-0088_u, Video-file SymonsJohnny_DaddyandPapa.mp4)
      Daddy & Papa is a one-hour documentary video that opens a candid window on the personal, cultural and political implications of gay fatherhood. From surrogacy, foster care and interracial adoption to the complexities of gay divorce and the legal battles around gay parenting, Daddy & Papa presents a revealing look at some of the gay fathers who are breaking new ground in the ever-changing landscape of the American family.
    - Ask Not, 2008; 73 minutes (Digital-materials RL10180-SET-0088_u, Video-file SymonsJohnny_AskNot.mp4)
      Award-winning PBS documentary Ask Not is a compelling exploration of the history and effects of the U.S. military's "don't ask, don't tell" policy. The film exposes the tangled political battles that led to the discriminatory law, and profiles courageous activists who fought for repeal.
  - Takesue, Kimi
    - 95 and 6 to Go, 2016; 85 minutes (Digital-materials RL10180-SET-0102_u, Video-file Takesue_Kimi_95_and_6_to_Go.mp4)
      A resilient Japanese-American senior in Hawai'i unexpectedly collaborates with his granddaughter on her stalled romantic screenplay, inspiring him to reflect on his life of love, loss, and perseverance. Humorous and poignant, the film prompts discussions on aging, identity, creativity, and inter-generational relationships.
  - Thompson, Shirley
    - Young Aspirations Young Artists, 1992; 32 minutes (Digital-materials RL10180-SET-0089_u, Video-file ThompsonShirley_YoungAspirationsYoungArtists_32min.mp4)
      The young artists of YA/YA paint true stories about their own lives, and create murals, fine art pieces, poetry and rap music that speak out on racism and reflect on community values. YA/YA, Inc. teaches these kids the chance to the chance to apprentice with professional artists, create public artworks, design merchandise, serve as cultural ambassadors, work as project managers, and mentor others in the arts. Ultimately, these kids learn to be professionally self-sufficient through creative self-expression. A powerful case for what happens when a great teacher empowers young people to find their own voices and shows them that they are indeed part of a larger world. Produced by Shirley Thompson.
    - Young Aspirations Young Artists, 1992; 56 minutes (Digital-materials RL10180-SET-0089_u, Video-file ThompsonShirley_YoungAspirationsYoungArtists_56min.mp4)
  - Walton, Pam
    - Gay Youth, 1996; 29 minutes (Digital-materials RL10180-SET-0090_u, Video-file WaltonPam_GayYouth.mp4)
      Gay Youth is a powerful and accessible educational video for high schools and colleges that breaks the silence surrounding adolescent homosexuality. This important film addresses the ways in which gay and lesbian teens are still at high risk for dropping out of school, drug and alcohol abuse, violence, homelessness, and suicide. By contrasting the tragic suicide of 20-year old Bobby Griffith, a gay teen who could not find acceptance, with the remarkable life of 17-year old Gina Gutierrez, Gay Youth shows us that information, acceptance, and support make enormous differences in the lives of these young people. Produced by Pam Walton.
    - Call To Witness, 2000; 58 minutes (Digital-materials RL10180-SET-0090_u, Video-file WaltonPam_CallToWitness.mp4)
      Call to Witness focuses on three extraordinary people who are willing to put their lives on the line for what they believe in. This video is an excellent discussion starter and historical document. It makes an important contribution to any religious or lgbt studies curricula. Produced by Pam Walton.
    - Liberty, 2006; 58 minutes (Digital-materials RL10180-SET-0090_u, Video-file WaltonPam_Liberty.mp4)
      This extraordinary work interweaves the stories of three close lesbian friends: Joyce Fulton (66), who died over the course of two years from a brain tumor; Mary Bell Wilson (79), who, with indefatigable courage, faces up to her own losing battle with lymphoma; and Nan Golub (58), a black-leather-jacketed, platinum-dyed New York City artist, very much alive. Libertydemystifies death, dispels misinformation about age and sexual orientation, and reminds us that life is worth living, even worth celebrating. Produced by Pam Walton.
    - Raging Grannies, 2010; 30 minutes (Digital-materials RL10180-SET-0090_u, Video-file WaltonPam_RagingGrannies.mp4)
      Raging Grannies is a lively and thought-provoking 30-minute documentary that tells the story of The Action League of the San Francisco Bay Area Peninsula. They are women over 50, some as old as 90, who are enraged by the conditions under which some people are forced to live, by threats to our environment, by war, and by injustice wherever they find it. Produced by Pam Walton.
    - Triptych, 2014; 29 minutes (Digital-materials RL10180-SET-0090_u, Video-file WaltonPam_Triptych.mp4)
      Art is one of the oldest activities on Earth, even predating science or math. But too often we forget it is a basic part of a balanced, healthy life. And women and art rarely get serious attention in our culture. Older women in art are virtually ignored. TRIPTYCH showcases 3 women who are vital and productive well into their seventies. Produced by Pam Walton.
  - Wong, Eddie
    - Chinatown Two Step, 1975; 16 minutes (Digital-materials RL10180-SET-0103_u, Video-file WongEddie_ChinatownTwoStep_VC.mp4)
      Capturing the all-American fervor of parade competition, Chinatown 2-Step profiles the Los Angeles Chinese Drum and Bugle Corps, an important fixture of the Chinese American community. Part of New Day's Visual Communications Collection.
    - Pieces of a Dream, 1974; 30 minutes (Digital-materials RL10180-SET-0103_u, Video-file WongEddie_PiecesOfADream_VC.mp4)
      A lyrical, expressive film history of Asian Pacific Americans on the Sacramento River delta. Part of New Day's Visual Communications Collection.
    - Wong Sinsaang, 1971; 12 minutes (Digital-materials RL10180-SET-0103_u, Video-file WongEddie_WongSinsaang_VC.mp4)
      WONG SINSAANG is a lyrical portrait of the filmmaker's father, a proprietor of a dry-cleaning business in Los Angeles' Silver Lake neighborhood. Part of New Day's Visual Communications Collection.
- Associated Digital Audiovisual Materials, 1970s-2000s; .5 Linear Feet 12 disks
  Audiovisual media are closed to use; access copies are available with advance notice.
  Please contact the Rubenstein Library before coming to use this collection.
  Consists entirely of digitized and born-digital media containing videos and still images relating to New Day Films.
  - Founders video, 2010; 00:04:30
    - Founders video, 2010; 00:04:30 (Digital-materials RL10180-SET-OD, Object RL10180-DVD-0003.iso)
    - Founders video, 2010; 00:04:30 (Box AV-07, Video-disc RL10180-DVD-0003)
  - New Day promotional video, 2010; 00:01:20
    - New Day Promo, 2010; 00:01:20 (Digital-materials RL10180-SET-OD, Object RL10180-DVD-0004.iso)
    - New Day Promo, 2010; 00:01:20 (Box AV-07, Video-disc RL10180-DVD-0004)
  - Digital images of New Day posters, catalogs, and other materials, 1970s-2000s; 548 MB
    - New Day posters, catalogs, and other materials, 1970s-2000s; 548 MB (Digital-materials RL10180-SET-OD, Object RL10180-OP-0002.iso)
    - New Day posters, catalogs, and other materials, 1970s-2000s; 548 MB (Box AV-07, Optical-disc RL10180-OP-0002)
  - Photographs of New Day Films cooperative members, 1970s-2000s; 545 MB
    - Photos of New Day members, 1970s-2000s; 545 MB (Digital-materials RL10180-SET-OD, Object RL10180-OP-0001.iso)
    - Photos of New Day members, 1970s-2000s; 545 MB (Box AV-07, Optical-disc RL10180-OP-0001)
  - Digitized and born-digital time-based media, 1971-2018
    - Digitized and born digital time-based media (Box AV-07, Digital-materials RL10180-EHD-0001)
    - Digitized and born digital time-based media (Box AV-07, Digital-materials RL10180-EHD-0002)
    - Digitized and born digital time-based media (Box AV-07, Digital-materials RL10180-EHD-0003)
    - Digitized and born digital time-based media (Box AV-07, Digital-materials RL10180-EHD-0004)